In the last lecture we added this order now button down there and it's working nice.
Son dersimizde imdi bu sipari dmesini aada dzenledik ve ok gzel alyor.
Now I want to make sure that once we click the button, we open this modal with the order summary.
imdi, dmeyi tkladnzda bu Modal Swiftie sipari zetini atmdan emin olmak istiyorum.
Now for that we obviously need a modal, we need a backdrop and we need to show some order summary,
Bunun iin akas modalaya ihtiyacmz var, bir zemin gerekiyor ve baz sipari zetini gstermemiz gerekiyor.
the idea behind the modal is to have a wrapping element which provides the styling which then simply
Hareketin arkasndaki fikir, daha sonra gstermek istediiniz herhangi bir ierik hakknda kendini saran ekillendirmeyi
wraps itself about any content we want to show
salayan bir sarma esine sahip olmaktr.
in that modal, that makes sense to me at least.
Bu modelde en azndan bana mantkl geliyor.
So I will create such a modal component and I want to create it in a new folder, in a components
Bu yzden byle bir kalc bileen oluturacam ve bileen klasrndeki yeni bir klasrde oluturmak ya
folder, I'll create a UI subfolder for some general UI
da genel iin alt klasr yazmak istiyorsanz onu istiyorum.
elements like the modal. So there I will add modal and in there, the modal.js file.
e gibi modeller Yani orada modal Che dosyasna modalite ekleyeceim.
As I said, we'll also need a backdrop so I will add a backdrop folder in the UI folder too, I didn't
Dediim gibi ayn zamanda bir zemin katman ekleyeceim zemin de olacak, nk Eifel ya da ikisi de
add the backdrop to the modal because we might reuse the backdrop in other places too,
motifin arka plann eklemedim, nk baka yerlerde de zemin de yeniden kullanabilirsin.
for example for the side drawer, for the navigation we're about to add later.
rnein navigasyon iin bir yan ekmece iin daha sonra eklemek zereyiz.
And in the backdrop folder, I therefore also to add a backdrop.js file.
Ve zemin klasrnde herkes iin bir zemin eklemek iin sadece izleyin.
Now we have these two components
imdi bu iki bileene sahibiz.
and let's start with the modal now. How should this modal component look like? It's going to be a functional
imdi modal ile balayalm. imdi bu Modal bileeni nasl ilevsel bir bileen olacak gibi
component
grnmelidir.
it doesn't have any state attached to it,
Ona bal herhangi bir devlet yok.
It just received some props and returned some jsx and it might surprise you
Sadece birka sahne ald ve baz GSX iade etti ve sizi artabilir.
but of course we import react from react here too and we export the modal function as the default
Fakat elbette yeniden eylemi buradan tekrar alyoruz ve modal ilevi bu dosyann
of this file.
varsaylan olarak veriliyoruz.
Now how does the jsx code look like then? The modal should simply be a div in the end which wraps itself
imdi GSX kodu nasl grnyorsa o zaman moton yalnzca herhangi bir ierik etrafnda dolaan
about around any content,
bir div olmaldr.
so a div which is wrapped around props.children and props.children really can be anything, can be our
div ve gerekten ocuklua dnk sahne her ey olabilir. Kendi bileenleri, modemi nasl
own components, can be some text, a paragraph, that is totally up to us how we use the modal and we can
kullandmz konusunda tamamen bize kalm bir paragraf olabilir ve orada bir ey geiremeyiz.
pass anything in there.
Pervane'nin ocuklarna sarlm bir
Of course the wrapping div should receive some styling to well, to look good in the end, to have a modal
Elbette sarc div modal bir grnm elde etmek iin sonunda iyi grnmek iin ok iyi stil
look.
alm olmaldr.
So for that I'm going to add a modal modal css file here and there,
Bunun iin burada ve orada bir modal modal C-s dosyas ekleyeceim.
I also share some css code which you can find attached to this video which you may just paste in
Ayrca, yaptrabileceiniz bu videoyla balantl olarak bulabileceiniz baz kod tohumlarn da
there.
paylayorum.
There we have our modal class and we can now see that this simply creates a fixed position modal, centers this
bir konum modals yarattn ve bize kk bir kutu glgesi verdiini ve ayrca Starling'in bazlarn daha geni
in the middle of the page and gives us a little box shadow and also changes some of the stylings for
ekran admnda deitirdiini gerekten de grebiliyoruz. aadaki SEUS snflarn aadaki gibi ie aktarabilirler.
broader screen, that really is all. With that, we can import the classes from that css file.
Orada modal snfmz var ve bunun artk sadece Sanders'n sayfann ortasnda sabit
So import classes from the modal css file and assign it to the wrapping div with the class name
Bylece, snflar modal C-s'den dosya olarak ie aktarn ve snf ad zniteliiyle sarmalam
attribute.
derinliine atayn.
So here we have classes.Modal with a capital M because that's the name of the css class.
Bu yzden, burada bir sermayeyle hareketsiz nokta snflar var nk C S S snfnn ad budur.
By the way make sure to save that css file after
Bu arada C S S'nin dtn kaydettiinizden emin olun.
you paste my content in there.
eriimi ieri yaptrrsn.
So that's the modal.js file,
Yani bu modal J S. dosya.
this will create such a modal.
Bu byle bir modal yaratacaktr.
Now let's add this modal right away
imdi biraz daha ekleyelim.
and the question of course is where in our application shall we add the modal?
Ve elbette ki soru, uygulamann neresinde kalb ekleyeceiz.
Well I would say we add in a place where we want to show it because that is the logical place
Onlara, gstermek istediimiz yeri eklediimizi syleyebilirim nk bu, ait olduu mantksal yer ve
where it belongs and where we probably have the state and the methods to control that display.
muhtemelen devlete gstermek zorunda olduumuz yerler ve bu ekran kontrol etme yntemleri.
So in our case, that's the burger builder,
Bu durumda bizim davamzda burger reticisi var.
let's simply add an import at the top modal from
'Nin st modalinde srayla ekleyin.
and now we need to navigate to that modal file which we can find in components,
Ve imdi, bileenlerde bulabileceimiz modal dosyaya gitmemiz gerekiyor.
UI modal and there, the modal.js file, as always without the file extension.
Siz modalisiniz ve dosya uzants olmadan her zaman olduu gibi faal olarak modal Jey var.
And then take the modal and add it to the jsx of the burger builder.
Ve sonra modl alp Bergere Boulder'n X'sine ekleyin.
Now here, we got our auxiliary component,
imdi burada yardmc bileene sahibiz.
we got the burger and the build controls,
Bergere ve toplu kontrollerimiz var.
Now here I'll simply add modal and of course this will soon be adjusted to not be visible all the time.
imdi burada sadece kalp ekleyecek ve tabii ki bu yaknda her zaman krmz grnmeyecek ekilde
Right
ayarlanacaktr.
now if we save this, we see the modal box here in the middle,
imdi bunu kaydedersek ortadaki kutu grrz.
of course without any content because as I said we should wrap this modal around the content we want to display
Tabii ki herhangi bir ierii yok nk dediim gibi, bu modu evirmeli ve grntlemeyi ve
and right now, it's a self-closing element and therefore not wrapping itself around anything.
okumay istiyoruz; imdi kendiliinden kapanan bir edir ve bu nedenle kendisini herhangi bir yere sarmamaktr.
The goal was to show the order summary and this burger builder file is already getting quite crowded
Hedef, sipari zetini gstermek ve inaat dosyasn datmak zaten olduka kalabalklat.
so I don't want to add the logic to transform this array into a nicely structured summary into this file,
Dolaysyla, bu diziyi bu dosyaya gzelce yaplandrlm bir zet haline dntrmek iin manta eklemek istemiyorum.
I will outsource it into its own component as this is generally a good practice in react, have granular
Yeniden hareket etmede genelde iyi bir uygulama olan paral odakl bileenlere sahip olduum iin onu
focused components.
kendi bileenine da aktaracam.
The component I want to create is an orderSummary component and I will add this
Oluturmak istediim bileen bir sipari zeti bileenidir ve bunu ekleyeceim.
under components burger and there, it makes sense to be added on the same level as build controls and
Andrew bileeninin burgeridir ve sanrm sanrm kontrol kontrolleri ve hamburger malzemeleri ile ayn
burger ingredients, I guess.
seviyede eklenmek mantkldr.
So let's add the order summary there and in there of course, the orderSummary.js file.
Bylece, sipari zetini orada ekleyelim ve elbette sipari dosyasnda zet nokta J'yi sipari edelim.
Now in here, I'll create a function orderSummary which receives some props and which then should have
Artk, baz sahne alan ve normal bir ilev gvdesine sahip olan
a normal function body because I'll have to execute some code to get the orderSummary, the ingredients
bir ilev sipari zetine baktnzda, sipari zetini doru formata almak
I get into the right format and so on.
iin baz kodlar altrmak zorunda kalacam.
Of course as always, we need to import react from react and we also want to export orderSummary as
Elbette ki her zaman olduu gibi yeniden ilemden yeniden aktarma almamz gerekiyor ve ayrca varsaylan dosya olarak
the file default,
sipari zetini vermek istiyoruz.
now how should we output the orderSummary, how should this look like? In the end,
imdi, sipari zetini, nasl kesin olarak neye benzediini nasl dkmeliyiz?
I want to have like a title which says your order, maybe a short text then a list of all the items
Sipariinizi ve belki ksa bir metni ieren bir balk istiyorum, daha sonra sipariteki tm
in the order and the price and then maybe a question,
elerin listesi ve fiyat ve sonra belki bir soru.
continue to checkout
Kontrol etmeye devam et.
and some buttons,
Ve baz dmeler.
so quite some stuff.
Bu yzden baz eyler.
Now I don't really need a wrapping element here
imdi burada gerekten bir sarma elemanna ihtiyacm yok.
therefore I will import my auxiliary element from aux, whoops hoc aux.
Bu nedenle yardmc elementimi, Agios Seahawks'tan alks belki alacam.
So now we can return some jsx code here with a wrapping auxiliary element and no worries,
imdi baz X kodunu bir kaydrma yardmc eleman ile geri getirebiliriz ve endielenmeyin.
we're going to add some logic in front of the return statement so that it makes sense to have a real
Return deyiminin nnde baz mantklar ekleyeceiz, bylece yalnzca return deyimi deil de
function body and not just the return statement.
gerek bir ilev gvdesinin olmas mantkl olacaktr.
So there, I will add a h3 tag where I say your order, below that, I want to add a paragraph where I simply
Bu yzden aada sipariinizi verdiimde cretsiz bir etiket ekleyeceim,
say
u
delicious burger with the following ingredients
paragraf ekleyerek u ieriklerle leziz burger sylyorum.
colon and now I want to add an unordered list which should contain well as many list items as needed
Colin ve imdi, burgerimle ilgili tm bilgileri ktlamak iin gereken birok liste esini iermek
to output all the information about my burger.
zere srasz bir liste eklemek istiyorum.
So for each ingredient, one list item.
Yani her madde iin bir liste esi.
Of course I could hardcode that there but I want to create this dynamically because we're always dynamic
kod zebilirim ancak bunu dinamik olarak oluturmak istiyorum nk hep dinamik ve
in react, so they're able to add a new variable, actually a constant because I don't plan on changing
tepki veriyoruz, bylece deimeyi planlamadm iin yeni bir deiken aslnda bir kavram ekleyebiliyoruz.
it,
Elbette orada
ingredientSummary which should take some ingredients
Baz maddeler almas gereken ierik zet.
I expect to get as props and basically map them into list items.
Tayc olarak almak ve temelde onlar liste elerine elemek istiyoruz.
Now for the ingredients, we're going to have the old problem that these are in an object format and not
Artk maddeler iin eski sorunumuzun bir nesne formatnda deil, bir dizi
an array.
olmas gerekiyor.
Now of course we could also create this component in a way to expect an array and transform
phesiz, elbette bu bileeni, bir diziyi bekleyip, Oracle zetine aktaracamz
the array in the burger builder where we will then pass it on to orderSummary,
burger oluturucudaki diziyi dntrmek iin bir yol oluturabiliriz.
but you can also do it the other way around and simply pass the object on and do the transformation
bir yolla da yapabilirsiniz ve nesneyi basite geip zet zet aknda dnm yapabilirsiniz.
in orderSummary.
Fakat bunu baka
It's the approach I'll follow because I believe that this allows us to keep the burger builder a bit leaner
Takip edeceim yaklam bu, bunun, nerede olmas gerektii her iki ynde de tartabilmenize ramen, derin oluturucuya
though you could argue for both directions where this should happen.
daha iyi bir yaln kalmam saladna inandmza inanyoruz.
So here, I expect to get my ingredients in a object format and in the end what I want to output is something
Dolaysyla burada ieriklerimi bir nesne formatnda almam bekliyorum ve nihayetinde unu
like this,
istiyorum:
I want to have a list item where I can basically say the name like salad it and then simply the number
Temelde adn satmak gibi syleyebileceim bir liste esine sahip olmak istiyorum ve daha sonra sadece bu tr
of ingredients of that type
malzemelerin saysn istiyorum.
and I would have a list item for each ingredient of course.
Ve elbette her madde iin bir liste esi olurdu.
Now when hard coding this, it would of course be easier because I could just hard code four list items
imdi, zor kodlama yaparsa, tabii ki daha kolay olurdu, nk bir listeye
and access the respective property on the ingredients object
girmek iin zor kod yazabilir ve maddeler nesnesinde ilgili mlke eriebilirim.
but I want to create it in a bit more flexible way,
Ancak daha esnek bir ekilde oluturmak istiyorum.
this is the output I want to have in the end though.
kt yine istiyorum istiyorum mu.
So what we can do is we can take the ingredients we get here and again use object keys to transform
Yapabildiimiz ey, elde ettiimiz malzemeleri alp buraya hcre ve benzeri anahtarlarn bir
this into an array of the keys of salad and so on.
dizisine dntrmek iin nesne anahtarlarn kullanabilmemiz.
Now as before, we want to map this,
imdi bunu haritalamak istemeden nce soruyorum.
We want to map this into an array of jsx elements at the end.
Bunu, sonunda bir dizi J S x esine elemek istiyoruz.
So we got the ingredients keys here as an input and we want to return
Dolaysyla, Ingredion anahtarlarn bir girdi olarak aldk ve geri dnmek istiyoruz.
well basically this list item I just defined here,
Peki temelde ben sadece burada bulabilirsiniz liste esi yok.
so let's grab the list item and add it here.
yleyse son maddeyi alalm ve buraya ekleyin.
Now how do we get the salad there or the ingredient name?
imdi hcrenin ieriine nasl ulaacaz.
Now that's just our ingredient key and the value is just props.ingredients and then access the ingredient
imdi, sadece bileen anahtarmz var ve deer yalnzca porsiyonun ierikleridir ve bileen anahtarna eriir ve
key and that's all.
hepsi bu kadar.
The only thing I'll add is I'll wrap the ingredient key here in a span because I want to capitalize it
bir madde anahtarn bir sreyle sarmak nk bunu byk harfle yazmak istiyorum, bu yzden ilk harfini bir
so turn the first letter into a capital one because in our ingredients array managed in the burger builder,
sermayeye evirelim, nk maddelerim dizisi burger yapmcs iinde ynetilen maddeler nesnesinde beni balar.
in the ingredients object, excuse me
Ekleyeceim tek ey, burada
we of course have salad, bacon and so on
Elbette salatas pastrmas vb. Var.
all starting with lowercase characters,
Hepsi kk harflerle balar.
now for outputting them, I want to have uppercase starting characters.
imdi onlar kartrsak, byk harf balang karakterleri isterim.
So therefore I wrap the name into a span so that I can use some inline stylings here and simply set
Dolaysyla, burada baz satr ii stilleri kullanabilmem iin adm bir aralkla saryorum ve bunu basite
this to a javascript object,
bir javascript nesnesine ayarlayalm.
that is why I have double curly braces, the outer pair is for marking a dynamic entry and the inner
Bu yzden ift kvrck parantezim var; d ifti iaretleme ve dinamik giri iin, i Cauley
curly braces are the javascript object,
parantezleri ise javascript nesnesi.
and there I will set the text-transform css property to capitalize,
Ve orada metni, C-s'leri maddi olarak yararlanmak iin ayarlayacam.
so simply using some inline styles here.
Dolaysyla, sadece baz satr ii stilleri burada kullanyor.
Now let me wrap this over multiple lines to make it a bit easier to read
imdi biraz okumay kolaylatrmak iin bunu birden ok satra sarmam iin bana izin verin.
so we have the list item here and in that list item, we have our span.
Bu yzden, burada bir liste esi var ve bu liste esinde Spanne sahibiz.
Now this is what I want to create, a list of these list items
imdi, bu liste elerinin listesini oluturmanz istediim ey bu.
and now we can simply output ingredients summary inside of that unordered list and I won't style this
Ve imdi, Ingredius zetini srasz listenin iinde ve bu nadir frsatta
unordered list because here for this rare occasion, I'll actually use the default style of all these elements
olduunuzdan veya aslnda tm bu unsurlarn varsaylan stilini kullandnzdan sipari zeti bileeni
which is why the orderSummary component doesn't even have its own OrderSummary css file
neden bile Aadaki gibi kendi sipari zeti Cs'ye sahip olmak.
though of course you are free to add one and style this to your needs.
Elbette kendi ihtiyalarnza bir tane ve stilist ekleyebilirsiniz.
And then I want to add a paragraph where I say continue to checkout, like that.
Ve sonra, byle bir gz atmaya devam ettiimi sylediim bir paragraf eklemek istiyorum.
Now let's go with this approach for now, with this orderSummary and let's use it in the burger builder.
imdi bu yaklamla bu sipari zetiyle devam edelim ve onu Bergere yapcda kullanalm.
I want to pass it between my modal opening and closing tags
Modal al ve kapan etiketlerim arasnda geirmek istiyorum.
SO let's first of all import this orderSummary component from our components folder and there from
Bu yzden ncelikle bu sipari zet bileenini bileenler klasrnden ie aktaralm ve
the burger folder, from the orders summary folder and the orders summary file, these import statements
sipari zeti dosyasndaki Bergere klasrnden bu ie aktarma ifadelerinin olduka
can get quite long.
uzun sre almasna izin verelim.
Now let's grab that orderSummary variable in which the save the import
imdi onu veya gvenlii ie aktaran zet bir deikeni ele alalm.
and let's go down to the modal and change this to have the opening and closing tag.
Ve modalete gidelim ve sadece al ve kapan etiketini alalm.
And in between, I now want to output my orderSummary of course as a self-closing component here.
Arasnda imdi sipari zetimi z-kapan bileeni olarak buradan kt olarak vermek istiyorum.
To work correctly,
Doru almak iin.
orderSummary of course needs to get the ingredients property because we're accessing ingredients on
Tabii sipari zeti, maddeler mlkiyetini elde etmek iin gerekiyor, nk burada
the props object here
pervane nesnesindeki malzemelere eriiyoruz.
in orderSummary.
Srayla zet.
So we need to pass our ingredients and we do get them from our state,
Dolaysyla, malzemelerimizi iletmek zorundayz ve onlar devletimizden alyoruz.
so this.state.ingredients.
Yani bu devlet malzemeleri.
Now let's see how that looks like, if we save all the files and we go back to our application,
imdi, tm hatalar biriktirsek ve bavurusuna dnersek bunun nasl bir hale geldiini grelim.
you'll see that we get a warning, we forgot to add the key to our array
Anahtar dizimize eklemeyi unuttuumuz bir uyar aldmz greceksiniz.
but generally, this looks good.
Ancak genellikle iyi grnyor.
And if I click these buttons, it updates the modal too
Dmeleri tklarsam modemi de gnceller.
and of course, that would be a good idea to not constantly show this modal but we're going to work
Ve elbette, bu modeli srekli gstermemek iyi bir fikir olurdu, ancak biz bunu ksa sre
on this soon.
iinde zerinde alacaz.
Let's fix this key error first
Bu anahtar alan veya ilkini dzeltelim.
and of course it's easy to fix,
Ve elbette dzeltmek kolaydr.
try this on your own. It's in the orderSummary of course, here on the list item
Bunu kendi banza deneyin, liste esinde elbette bir sipari zeti olsun.
we have to add a key and that key should be a unique key
Bir anahtar eklemek zorundayz ve l anahtar benzersiz bir anahtar olmaldr.
as you know, now let's simply use the igKey, so salad and so on as a key here
Bildiiniz gibi imdi basite IGY anahtarn salam ve bu ekilde bir anahtar olarak kullanalm.
and with that, the warning should be gone.
Ve bununla birlikte uyar gitmi olmal.
Now the next step is to make sure that we don't always see the modal but that we can add it or show
imdi bir sonraki adm, modelin her zaman grmediimizden, ancak onu ekleyip gsterebileceimizden emin
it
olmaktr.
once you click order now.
imdi sipari verdikten sonra.